Justin Moore

Denver Colorado

Cell: 970-409-6168

email: justin.m.moore5896@gmail.com

https://github.com/Jmo5896 | https://jmo5896.github.io/current-portfolio/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-moore-3ab083158/

Professional Summary

Reliable and inventive Entry Level Web Developer with a strong customer service record and unyielding work ethic. Highly knowledgeable in a comprehensive variety of computer languages, website construction mechanics as well as continued maintenance. Skillfully adept at conveying technical information in presentation settings with small and large groups. Able to focus on the bigger picture in terms of goals with a step by step process in which to achieve desired results.

Technical Skills

HTML experience: 4 months
CSS experience: 4 months
Bootstrap experience: 4 months
JavaScript experience: 4 months
jQuery experience: 4 months
Express experience: 4 months
Node.js experience: 4 months
Handlebars experience: 4 months
mySQL experience: 4 months
MongoDB experience: 4 months

React.js experience: 4 months

Recent Projects

- **Body Book** (group project) | https://github.com/Jmo5896/Project-2
 - This is one of my first full-stack projects. My team and I wanted to build a place where you could store medical information that is important to have in an emergency situation but may be hard to recall.
 - Skills Used: HTML, CSS, Ulkit, Handlebars, JavaScript, ¡Query, Node.js, mySQL, Sequelize, PassPort.js
- Train Scheduler | https://github.com/Jmo5896/Train-Scheduler
 - This is a project I threw together to learn how to use Firebase. You can enter in the name of a train, it's destination, the first arrival time, and how often it makes its loop. The app will then tell you when the next arrival will be and how many minutes away it is (in real time).
 - Skills Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase
- GifTastic | https://github.com/Jmo5896/GifTastic
 - This little project was my first attempt at utilizing an API with ajax calls in jQuery. The basic concept is enter in a category you want to search, when you hit add a button will be created with the category name you added. When you click the button it will pull up the top 12 gifs in the given category.
 - Skills Used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery
- **Bamazon** | https://github.com/Jmo5896/Bamazon
 - The original purpose of this project was to teach myself mySQL, and to make a working back-end application that will be able to track inventory and organize products. I created three different views for the data: customer, manager, and supervisor. This is a completely back-end project so please checkout the readMe in the Github repo.
 - Skills Used: JavaScript and Node

Core Qualifications

- Notable leadership and presentation abilities.
- Proficient facility with Windows and MAC operating systems.
- Strong knowledge of Microsoft Office and Excel.
- Sound familiarity with using MySQL.
- Confident knowledge of web programming languages including Node.Js, MongoDB, mySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, and React.
- Profound creative and analytical problem-solving and troubleshooting skills.
- High verbal and written communication skills.

Experience

Free Lance Web Developer - University of Denver Bootcamp Program

April 2018- July 2018

Denver. CO

- Learned from the ground up; how to build a full-stack website, acquired talent for identifying errors and preparing authentication records
- Brought out the strengths of others in groups when leading group projects
- Taught and learned from peers on various class projects.
- Understand the importance of efficient problem solving and troubleshooting under strict deadlines
- Gained knowledge of both front and back-end processes

CDL Driver - Copper Mountain

November 2017-April 2018 Previous Nov 2016- April 2017, Nov 2015- April 2016 Frisco. CO

- Comprehended the importance of sticking to a timed route and how to drive safely in hazardous conditions
- Mastered the ability to efficiently map my own route on the fly while operating an on-call pick-up service
- Interacted with hundreds of guests daily, gaining excellent guest service skills.

Transportation Supervisor Holland America Princess Yukon Alaska Division - Denali Princess Wilderness Lodge April 2017-Sept 2017

Denali, AK

- Cultivated leadership experience while overseeing up to 35 drivers.
- Experienced the importance of detailed planning and how to come up with quick solutions on the spot for situations that may arise
- Communicated across other hotel departments on property and various Alaska locations.

CDL Driver/Guide Holland America Princess Yukon Alaska Division - Denali Princess Wilderness Lodge June 2016- Oct 2016, Previous April 2015-Sept 2015

Denali, AK

- Earned CDL through company training program.
- Advanced my understanding of the importance of safety while transporting up to 56 guests or employees at any given time

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Program - University of Denver

April 2018-July2018 Denver, CO

Some College - Brigham Young University *Aug 2008-July 2009, Sept 2013-April 2015 Rexburg, ID*

• GPA 3.68 on a 4.0 scale